{"response_code": 0,
"results":

[{
        "question": "The Greek word 'Liber' means",
        "correct_answer": "book",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Library",
            "building",
            "brains"
        ]
    },

    {
        "question": "Library started in Nigeria in?",
        "correct_answer": "1950",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "1956",
            "1914",
            "1960"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Libraries were developed as far as",
        "correct_answer": "3000BC",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "4000BC",
            "2000BC",
            "6000BC"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the father of Nigeria library",
        "correct_answer": "John Harris",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Dr Henry",
            "Kalu Okorie",
            ""
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The part of a book that contains additional information to the content is",
        "correct_answer": "Subsidiaries",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Body of text",
            "Serial",
            "Cover"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The abridged dictionary is usually called.... dictionary",
        "correct_answer": "desk",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "chair",
            "room",
            "office"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following is the dictionary useful",
        "correct_answer": "Etymology",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Organization",
            "Indexing",
            "Cataloging"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": ".... is the most important part of a book",
        "correct_answer": "the text",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "the title page",
            "the bibliography",
            "the appendix"
        ]
    },

    {
        "question": "Which part of the book contains the call number",
        "correct_answer": "Spine",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Jacket", "Back cover", "Blurb"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is not a reference material",
        "correct_answer": "Journal",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Dictionaries", "Encyclopedia", "Bibliography"]
    },
    {
        "question": "The loan period for students is how many weeks",
        "correct_answer": "2",
        "incorrect_answers": ["4", "6", "8"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can users photocopy pages of interest",
        "correct_answer": "Reprographic unit",
        "incorrect_answers": ["ICT", "Database", ""]
    }

    ,
    {
        "question": "Books about general knowledge is",
        "correct_answer": "Encyclopedia",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Dictionary", "Bibliography", "Directory"]
    },
    {
        "question": "How many division are in a library",
        "correct_answer": "7",
        "incorrect_answers": ["10", "5", "4"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Intellectual Property refers to creation of the",
        "correct_answer": "mind",
        "incorrect_answers": ["book", "copyright", ""]
    },
    {
        "question": "The borrowers ticket allows how many books for undergraduates",
        "correct_answer": "3",
        "incorrect_answers": ["5", "10", "6"]
    },
    {
        "question": "All these are for easy retrieval except",
        "correct_answer": "Referencing",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Bibliography", "Indexing", "Abstracting"]
    },
    {
        "question": "How many arrangements of catalog cards do we have",
        "correct_answer": "2",
        "incorrect_answers": ["5", "3", "5"]
    },
    {
        "question": "The LC scheme was developed by the Library of Congress in",
        "correct_answer": "1902",
        "incorrect_answers": ["1914", "1918", ""]
    },
    {
        "question": "Reading maketh a full man, conference a ready man, and writing an exact man. Who made the statement?",
        "correct_answer": "Francis Bacon",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Padre Pio", "George Bolingo", "Emmanuel Macron"]
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Francis Bacon, .... maketh an exact man",
        "correct_answer": "writing",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Reading", "conference", "learning"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Reading speed is calculated in...",
        "correct_answer": "words per minute",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Words per hour", "time sequence", "Words per second"]
    },
    {
        "question": "The administration of a university is headed by a...",
        "correct_answer": "vice-chancellor",
        "incorrect_answers": ["registrar", "governor", "boxer"]
    },
    {
        "question": ".... refers to words that have multiple meanings",
        "correct_answer": "polysemy",
        "incorrect_answers": ["polyphonic", "poly words", "polysauraus"]
    },
    {
        "question": ".... refers to words that are spelled alike",
        "correct_answer": "homographs",
        "incorrect_answers": ["homophones", "homonyms", "synonyms"]
    },
    {
        "question": ".... defined the university as the assemblage of strangers from all parts of the world in one spot for the purpose of communication and circulation of thought",
        "correct_answer": "Henry Newman",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Wole Soyinka", "John Brian", "Mary Morsel"]
    },
    {
        "question": ".... refers to how words mean in a language",
        "correct_answer": "semantics",
        "incorrect_answers": ["antics", "phonetic", "phonics"]
    },
    {
        "question": "A verb may either be in the.... or.... voice",
        "correct_answer": "active or passive",
        "incorrect_answers": ["transitive or intransitive", "lexical or auxiliary", "long or short"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Verb forms that function as nouns are called....",
        "correct_answer": "gerunds",
        "incorrect_answers": ["infinitive", "participle", "modifier"]
    },
    {
        "question": "A list of materials consulted by the author in the course of writing a book is called",
        "correct_answer": "bibliography",
        "incorrect_answers": ["appendix", "index", "copyright"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the head of the administration department in a public library?",
        "correct_answer": "director of library services",
        "incorrect_answers": ["public librarian", "reference librarian", "coordinator of public library"]
    },
    {
        "question": "A light paper wrapping covering a book is called...",
        "correct_answer": "jacket",
        "incorrect_answers": ["cover", "blurb", "Spine"]
    },
    {
        "question": ".... is not found in the cover of a book",
        "correct_answer": "dedication",
        "incorrect_answers": ["title of the book", "name of author", "summary of the book"]
    },
    {
        "question": "One of these is not found on the title page",
        "correct_answer": "ISBN",
        "incorrect_answers": ["author's name", "Title", "sub-title"]
    },
    {
        "question": "The copyright page contains all but one of the following information",
        "correct_answer": "Title",
        "incorrect_answers": ["ISBN", "CIP", "Publishers address"]
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year was the Library of Congress classification scheme devised",
        "correct_answer": "1897",
        "incorrect_answers": ["1912", "1771", "1809"]
    },
    {
        "question": ".... invented the Dewey Decimal Classification",
        "correct_answer": "Melvin Dewey",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Charles Dewey", "Thomas Dewey", "Gandra Dewey"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Updated and seldom used books have withdrawn from the library is known as....",
        "correct_answer": "weeding",
        "incorrect_answers": ["shelving", "circulating", "guiding"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Copyright instruction is located at... of a book",
        "correct_answer": "verso of a title page",
        "incorrect_answers": ["title page", "blurb", "book cover"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Where a person deliberately uses someone else's language, ideas, or other materials without citing is....",
        "correct_answer": "Plagiarism",
        "incorrect_answers": ["piracy", "theft", "plagirism"]
    },
    {
        "question": "When an individual reproduces and sells an existing book without the consent of the author and publisher for profit, it is called....",
        "correct_answer": "piracy",
        "incorrect_answers": ["plagiarism", "theft", "book theft"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Books misplaced on the shelves by readers are restored; this work is referred to as....",
        "correct_answer": "shifting",
        "incorrect_answers": ["shelving", "stock verification", "shelf rectification"]
    },
    {
        "question": "They are... types of complement",
        "correct_answer": "3",
        "incorrect_answers": ["1", "2", "4"]
    },
    {
        "question": "A basic sentence is also called a....",
        "correct_answer": "main clause",
        "incorrect_answers": ["fragment", "language", "dynamic verb"]
    },
    {
        "question": "The.... sentence states a fact or opinion",
        "correct_answer": "declarative",
        "incorrect_answers": ["incisive", "exclamatory", "interrogative"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a verb of action?",
        "correct_answer": "dynamic verb",
        "incorrect_answers": ["static verb", "ordinary verb", "modified verb"]
    },
    {
        "question": "A simple sentence in the context of language contains a subject and a....",
        "correct_answer": "finite verb",
        "incorrect_answers": ["infinite verb", "articulate verb", "addictive verb"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Dynamic verbs are of two classes",
        "correct_answer": "transitive and intransitive",
        "incorrect_answers": ["passive and inpassive", "cognitive and incognitive", "nominative and innominative"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Complete the sentence. The thief crept.... into the room",
        "correct_answer": "stealthily",
        "incorrect_answers": ["loudly", "cheekily", "impromptly"]
    },
    {
        "question": "A complex sentence has one main clause and at least one.... clause",
        "correct_answer": "subordinate",
        "incorrect_answers": ["coordinate", "inordinate", "ordinate"]
    },
    {
        "question": "In terms of structure, there are.... types of sentences",
        "correct_answer": "5",
        "incorrect_answers": ["4", "3", "2"]
    },
    {
        "question": "They are... kinds of objects in English grammar",
        "correct_answer": "2",
        "incorrect_answers": ["4", "6", "8"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which part of a book connects the front and back covers",
        "correct_answer": "spine",
        "incorrect_answers": ["blurb", "title page", "jacket"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which section of the library is responsible for the purchase of books?",
        "correct_answer": "acquisition",
        "incorrect_answers": ["reference", "cataloguing", "circulation"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Central Bank of Nigeria library Abuja is an example of a....",
        "correct_answer": "special library",
        "incorrect_answers": ["academic library", "school library", "national library"]
    },
    {
        "question": "ISBN means....",
        "correct_answer": "international standard book number",
        "incorrect_answers": ["international serial book number", "interlibrary standard book name", "none of the above"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the correct word to complete the sentence: 'The ___________ mountain peak was a sight to behold.'",
        "correct_answer": "majestic",
        "incorrect_answers": ["majestical", "majestically", "majesty"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the correct form of the verb to complete the sentence: 'Neither of the two friends ________ happy with the outcome.'",
        "correct_answer": "is",
        "incorrect_answers": ["are", "am", "were"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the appropriate word to complete the sentence: 'The novel was so ________ that I couldn't put it down'.",
        "correct_answer": "captivating",
        "incorrect_answers": ["captivated", "captivation", "captivate"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the correct sentence structure:",
        "correct_answer": "The cat sat gracefully on the table.",
        "incorrect_answers": ["On the table, the cat sat gracefully.", "Sat the cat gracefully on the table.", "Gracefully sat the cat on the table."]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the correct possessive form of the noun: 'The professor commended ________ students' efforts.'",
        "correct_answer": "students'",
        "incorrect_answers": ["student'", "students's", "student's"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Fill in the correct verb, the remains of the king.... lying in state now",
        "correct_answer": "is",
        "incorrect_answers": ["will be", "had been", "were"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Fill in the correct verb, I am..... a letter to my best friend",
        "correct_answer": "writing",
        "incorrect_answers": ["wrote", "written", "write"]
    },
    {
        "question": "The Akwa Ibom State University has how many ebooks",
        "correct_answer": "136,000",
        "incorrect_answers": ["190,000", "40,000", "56,000"]
    },
    {
        "question": "How many phases in the history of the library do we have",
        "correct_answer": "3",
        "incorrect_answers": ["4", "2", "5"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is not a listening cue",
        "correct_answer": "Attentive",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Verbal", "Non-verbal", "Implicit"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Cues of sequence involve the following except",
        "correct_answer": "also",
        "incorrect_answers": ["first", "second", "next"]
    },
    {
        "question": "The type of reading that involves screening the passage very urgently to locate specific information in a broad writeup is",
        "correct_answer": "Scanning",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Speed reading", "Skimming", "Critical reading"]
    },
    {
        "question": "The following are functions of reading except",
        "correct_answer": "For attentive listening",
        "incorrect_answers": ["To increase Knowledge", "For didactic experience", "To enrich the mind"]
    },
    {
        "question": "How many monophthongs do we have",
        "correct_answer": "12",
        "incorrect_answers": ["10", "6", "5"]
    },
    {
        "question": "How many diphthongs do we have",
        "correct_answer": "8",
        "incorrect_answers": ["11", "12", "9"]
    },
    {
        "question": "How many triphthongs do we have",
        "correct_answer": "5",
        "incorrect_answers": ["9", "12", "6"]
    },
    {
        "question": "The sound /p/,/b/ is a",
        "correct_answer": "plosive",
        "incorrect_answers": ["fricative", "affricate", "glottal"]
    },
    {
        "question": "The sound /f/,/s/,/v/ is a",
        "correct_answer": "fricative",
        "incorrect_answers": ["plosive", "affricate", "glottal"]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the correct stress for Request",
        "correct_answer": "reQUEST",
        "incorrect_answers": ["REquest", "", ""]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the correct stress for unreasonable",
        "correct_answer": "un-REA-sonable",
        "incorrect_answers": ["unreason-ABLE", "UNreasonable", ""]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the correct stress for establishment",
        "correct_answer": "es-TAB-lishment",
        "incorrect_answers": ["ES-tablishment", "establish-MENT", ""]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the correct stress for protector",
        "correct_answer": "proTECTor",
        "incorrect_answers": ["protectOR", "PROtectot", ""]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the correct rhyme for wire",
        "correct_answer": "hire",
        "incorrect_answers": ["mill", "mice", ""]
    },
    {
        "question": "An essay that gives an account of something is",
        "correct_answer": "Narrative essay",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Descriptive essay", "Argumentative essay", "Expository essay"]
    },
    {
        "question": "An essay that explains an issue, a theory, or a process is",
        "correct_answer": "Expository essay",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Descriptive essay", "Narrative essay", "Argumentative essay"]
    },
    {
        "question": "How many types of letters do we have",
        "correct_answer": "3",
        "incorrect_answers": ["2", "5", ""]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which library is also referred to as monastic",
        "correct_answer": "Medieval",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Antiquity", "Modern", ""]
    },
    {
        "question": "How many faculties/resource rooms do we have in Akwa Ibom University",
        "correct_answer": "7",
        "incorrect_answers": ["5", "10", "4"]
    },
    {
        "question": "The Lagos Town council partnered with the British Council in what year",
        "correct_answer": "1946",
        "incorrect_answers": ["1959", "1940", "1960"]
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Dewey's decimal classification, the number 300 stands for",
        "correct_answer": "Social Science",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Religion", "Language", "Arts"]
    },
    {
        "question": "'Delimitation denotes.....",
        "correct_answer": "Setting boundaries beyond which an essay does not go",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Setting boundaries for community",
            "Removing limitation on book",
            "Makes sure an art does not have imitation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The ..... order seems most suited for a narrative essay",
        "correct_answer": "Chronological",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Abstract", "Review", "Introduction"]
    },
    {
        "question": "A sentence definition comprises the... and ...",
        "correct_answer": "genus and differentia",
        "incorrect_answers": ["cause and effect", "comparison and contrast", "merits and demerits"]
    },
    {
        "question": "... are notes taken during formal meetings",
        "correct_answer": "Minutes",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Memos", "Acronyms", "Mnemonics"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Declarative statements are also known as",
        "correct_answer": "Statements",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Concise statement", "Imposed statement", "All of the above"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the correct form of the sentence. Ememobong does not like beans",
        "correct_answer": "Declarative",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Interrogative", "Empirical", "Exclamatory"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the correct form of the sentence. Which of the pencil is yours?",
        "correct_answer": "Interrogative",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Declarative", "Empirical", "Exclamatory"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the correct form of the sentence. The book is on the table",
        "correct_answer": "Declarative",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Interrogative", "Empirical", "Exclamatory"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the correct form of the sentence. Come here at once!",
        "correct_answer": "Imperative",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Declarative", "Interrogative", "Exclamatory"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the sentence pattern that corresponds to the sentence. The policeman bought a new pistol ",
        "correct_answer": "SVOA",
        "incorrect_answers": ["SVC", "SV", "SVO"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the sentence pattern that corresponds to the sentence. The toad moved ",
        "correct_answer": "SV",
        "incorrect_answers": ["SVOC", "SVOO", "SVC"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the sentence type. The work stops when it rains, but the tools are kept very handy",
        "correct_answer": "Compound-complex",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Compound", "Multiple", "Simple"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the sentence type. The thief has been caught",
        "correct_answer": "Simple",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Multiple", "Conjoined", "Concrete"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is not a part of Preliminary page",
        "correct_answer": "Index",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Table of content", "Preface", "Fly leave"]
    },
    {
        "question": "The part of the page numbered in Roman figures is",
        "correct_answer": "Preliminary page",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Cover page", "Subsidiaries", "Serials"]
    },
    {
        "question": "The visible part of a book that contains the title and author's name is",
        "correct_answer": "the spine",
        "incorrect_answers": ["the cover", "the dust jacket", "fly leaves"]
    },
    {
        "question": "...... is a page that contains words that are not familiar",
        "correct_answer": "Glossary",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Appendices", "Index", "Reference"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which service equips its users with adequate knowledge about the library",
        "correct_answer": "User education service",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Current awareness service", "Reference service", "Internet Service"]
    },
    {
        "question": "The Britannica Encyclopedia was published in Scotland in",
        "correct_answer": "1968",
        "incorrect_answers": ["1959", "1940", "1989"]
    },
    {
        "question": "... is the page immediately after the title page",
        "correct_answer": "Copyright page",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Dedication", "Acknowledgement", "Table of Content"]
    },
    {
        "question": "... is the most important part of a book",
        "correct_answer": "the text",
        "incorrect_answers": ["the title page", "the bibliography", "the Appendix"]
    },
    {
        "question": "A library service that repairs damaged books so they can be returned to the shelves is...",
        "correct_answer": "Bindery service",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Fixing service", "Make-up service", "All of the above"]
    },
    {
        "question": ".... is the administrative head of a public library",
        "correct_answer": "Director of library service",
        "incorrect_answers": ["General manager", "General librarian", "All of the above"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the National Library of Nigeria located",
        "correct_answer": "Abuja",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Lagos", "Port Harcourt", "Enugu"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Who among the following does book shelving in the library",
        "correct_answer": "The library assistant",
        "incorrect_answers": ["The librarian", "Typist", "Security"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which discipline uses Elizabeth Moy's classification",
        "correct_answer": "Law",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Linguistics", "Medical", "Engineering"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has credit for the Library of Congress classification",
        "correct_answer": "Dr. Herbert Putnam",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Dr. Ken Kloret", "Dr. JoneOdeley", "Dr. Winter Welsh"]
    },
    {
        "question": "How many types of libraries do we have",
        "correct_answer": "7",
        "incorrect_answers": ["6", "4", "2"]
    },
    {
        "question": "A library whose collections are limited to only one subject or group is...",
        "correct_answer": "Special library",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Private library", "Public library", "School library"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technique helps the authors to trace the source of a work and an unauthorized duplication of the original work",
        "correct_answer": "Digital Water Marks",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Encryption scheme"]
    },
    {
        "question": ".... is regarded as the father of English",
        "correct_answer": "John Olen",
        "incorrect_answers": ["John Drydem", "Geoffrey Chaucer", "William Shakespeare"]
    },
    {
        "question": "R.S.V.P is a.... acronym",
        "correct_answer": "French",
        "incorrect_answers": ["German", "Latin", "Spanish"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Verbs such as dance, eat, write are called... verbs",
        "correct_answer": "Lexical",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Modal", "Auxiliary", "Uniform"]
    },
    {
        "question": ".... is a type of library",
        "correct_answer": "All of the above",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Academic", "National", "Public"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following best identifies the library user",
        "correct_answer": "All of the above",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Reader", "Client", "Patron"]
    },
    {
        "question": ".... is the largest library in the world",
        "correct_answer": "Library of Congress",
        "incorrect_answers": ["British library", "Bibliotheque", "National library"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Book that provides information about people and culture is",
        "correct_answer": "Atlas",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Almanac", "Gazetteer", "Gazette"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Book that provides information about geographical location is",
        "correct_answer": "Gazetteer",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Almanac", "Gazette", "Atlas"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Book that provides information about basic data and statistics on countries is",
        "correct_answer": "Almanac",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Gazetteer", "Gazette", "Atlas"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Book that provides information about day-to-day activities of the government is",
        "correct_answer": "Gazette",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Almanac", "Gazetteer", "Atlas"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Lending policy for staff is",
        "correct_answer": "3 books in 1 month",
        "incorrect_answers": ["5 books in 2 months", "2 books in 2 weeks", "3 books in 3 weeks"]
    },
    {
        "question": "On Saturday, the library opening is from",
        "correct_answer": "8am - 4pm",
        "incorrect_answers": ["8am - 10pm", "8am - 5pm"]
    },
    {
        "question": "... is an internet-based plagiarism preventer",
        "correct_answer": "Turnitin",
        "incorrect_answers": ["IP", "WIPO"]
    },
    {
        "question": "The act of preparing a record that points at the location of materials in the library is",
        "correct_answer": "Indexing",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Bibliography", "Cataloguing", "Abstracting"]
    },
    {
        "question": "The process of recording and bringing together all characteristics of information material to enable easy access is",
        "correct_answer": "Cataloguing",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Bibliography", "Indexing", "Abstracting"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Books about people are",
        "correct_answer": "Biography",
        "incorrect_answers": ["Dictionary", "Directory", "Encyclopedia"]
    }
]}